Hello everyone welcome back to our post square SQL tutorial series so today, we're going to explore the select statement
In the one of the most fundamental comments in the post square SQL and use for each of the data from the post square SQL data set
So these are simple understanding for select for the post square SQL
This statement is used to query data from
On our multiple in the database and it allows us to specify this column to retrieve the filtering condition and
Now just let's explore how it works with some example, okay?
So first of all, I can create for the first example for selecting all the columns from the each table, okay?
So now just go for here and first of all here
I can just type for the select. So we can use the select and then
Start for the multiple sign then the multiplication
And choose from the table using the
Employees, okay, so here perfect and now
Need to select this statement to get all the columns for the employees table, okay?
And here this is the asterisk for the multiplication side
We can select all the columns, okay, so here I can just select and
Adjust
This is the operation is successful and the post square SQL
We can
Although and the column from the employee table as the result, okay, so
This is the complete for the first example, okay, and next step here
I can use for the selecting for the specific columns, okay?
So here it's just open for and just go into the new query and here just open for the employee idea, okay?
Then the first name and the last name, okay?
So now just going for here select and then type
It's the first name type the employee idea, okay? So
EMP
This ID and also here this on
First name and also here the
Last name, okay?
So here this on the last name and choose for the employee statement and here
the selection
Only for the employee idea
First name is selected column for the employee's daily and now here select the mix
To execute the data you can see here only show for the data query
For the employee the first name and the last name if the quotation is successfully
Post grade will return all the way in the specific column in the results here, okay?
So here only choose for the there is the same salary, okay? So
Sully column, okay? So now just use this column and now select and execute now
You can see here only green column single column and the seller column, okay?
So here also applying for the filtering condition. So now let's see how it works. So first of all there
I can create for selecting
Multiplication sign from here the employee stable and
We can use the very close for the department, okay? So this department from the equal to
Here use for the department of the schedule, okay?
So now
Defend perfectly and select a statement
Will you take all the columns from the employee stable or the department column is equal to
Now here I can select the data query and
Then execute you can see here the print for the department of the civil and they are complete
this
Statement and the post grade SQL will return
For put all the row that made the condition in the results sheet, okay?
So here in the session is completely done and here I have perfectly applied for the select statement in the post grade
SQL would sound practical example, okay?
So I hope you find this tutorial helpful. So stay tuned for more post grade SQL tips and tricks, okay?
So thank you for watching and happy data query, okay?